Guide to the John Steinbeck Collection, 1902-1979 M0263
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
John Steinbeck collection
1902-1979
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Steinbeck, John
M0263
8.5 Linear Feet
The collection is primarily letters and documents written by Steinbeck to family, friends and business associates. Also included are letters written to Steinbeck and letters written about him. Includes manuscripts and typescripts of works by Steinbeck, proofs of books, tearsheets, and photocopies of published works by him. Reviews of Steinbeck's work, articles about him, press coverage of his travels, memorabilia, photographs, and artwork complete the collection.
Arrangement
Data organization: Correspondence, 1928-1972 (boxes 1-8), Literary manuscripts, 1923-1975 (boxes 8-12), Photographs, artwork and ephemera, 1902-1979 (boxes 12-17).
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection is primarily letters and documents written by Steinbeck to family, friends and business associates. Also included are letters written to Steinbeck and letters written about him. Includes manuscripts and typescripts of works by Steinbeck, proofs of books, tearsheets, and photocopies of published works by him. Reviews of Steinbeck's work, articles about him, press coverage of his travels, memorabilia, photographs, and artwork complete the collection.
Biography / Administrative History
John Ernst Steinbeck was born in Salinas, California 27 February 1902. He was the author of short stories and novels, of which some became plays and films. He died in New York City 20 December 1968.
Acquisition Information
Gifts and purchases from various sources.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Steinbeck, John
- John Steinbeck to Margery and Nathaniel Benchley, 1965 (3 lvs.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- John Steinbeck to Katherine Beswick, Winter 1927-May 1928 (12 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- John Steinbeck to Katherine Beswick, Feb/March 1928-Spring 1928 (12 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- John Steinbeck to Katherine Beswick, June 1928-Dec. 1928 (12 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- John Steinbeck to Katherine Beswick, late 1928 (11 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 5)
- John Steinbeck to Katherine Beswick, Jan. 1929-Feb. 1929 (12 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- John Steinbeck to Katherine Beswick, late Feb. 1929-May 1929 (14 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- John Steinbeck to Katherine Beswick, Aug. 1929-May 1930 (15 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- John Steinbeck to Katherine Beswick, July 1930-January 1932 (17 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- John Steinbeck to Robert Cathcart, Jan.1, 1928-March 1 [1929] (17 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- John Steinbeck to Barnaby Conrad, Dec. 29, 1952-March 30, 1968 (13 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- John Steinbeck to Eric Goldman, ca. Dec. 1964 (3 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- John Steinbeck to [Paul] Griffin, April 22, 1942 (2 lvs); John Steinbeck to Dr. Grommon, May 24, 1948 (1 leaf) (Box 1, Folder 13)
- John Steinbeck to Harry Guggenheim, Aug. 1963-Sept. 9, 1965 (10 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 14)
- John Steinbeck to Harry Guggenheim, Sept. 20, 1965-Nov. 5, 1965 (10 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 15)
- John Steinbeck to Harry Guggenheim, Nov. 6, 1965-Nov. 1965 (13 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- John Steinbeck to Harry Guggenheim, Dec. 1965-Jan. 1966 (8 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 17)
- John Steinbeck to Harry Guggenheim, Feb. 1966 (12 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 18)
- John Steinbeck to Harry Guggenheim, April 1966-July 1966 (13 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 19)
- John Steinbeck to Harry Guggenheim, Aug. 1966-Nov. 1966 (14 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 20)
- John Steinbeck to Harry Guggenheim, Dec. 1966-Jan. 19, 1967 (15 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 21)
- John Steinbeck to Harry Guggenheim, Jan. 23, 1967-March 18, 1967 (12 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 22)
- John Steinbeck to Harry Guggenheim, March 23, 1967-May 3, 1967 (10 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 23)
- John Steinbeck affidavit for visa for Alexander Hackenschmied, 1941 (2 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 24)
- John Steinbeck to Mort R. Lewis, Nov. 26-Dec. 16, 1952 (photocopies) (3 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 25)
- John Steinbeck to Theodore Lilienthol, ca Sept. 1937-May 13, 1938, nd. (8 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 26)
- John Steinbeck to A. Amasa (Ted) Miller, Jan. 1929-March 1930 (11 lvs) (Box 1, Folder 27)
- John Steinbeck to A. Amasa (Ted) Miller, April 1930-Nov. 1930 (13 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 1)
- John Steinbeck to A. Amasa (Ted) Miller, Dec. 1930-mid-1931 (15 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- John Steinbeck to A. Amasa (Ted) Miller, August 1931-1936 (12 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 3)
- John Steinbeck to Michael Morris, 1964 (4 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 4)
- John Steinbeck to Wilbur Needham, 1939 (2 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 5)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, 1931-1936 (13 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, 1937 (12 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 7)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, February 1938-July 1938 (15 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, August-December, 1938 (10 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 9)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, January-April 10, 1939 (10 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 10)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, April 15-July, 1939 (12 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 11)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, August-October, 1939 (10 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 12)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, November-December, 1939 (9 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 13)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, January-February, 1940 (11 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 14)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, March-May, 1940 (13 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 15)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, June-October, 1940 (13 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 16)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, November-December, 1940 (10 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 17)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, January-February 7, 1941 (10 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 18)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, February-July, 1941 (13 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 19)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, August-December, 1941 (12 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 20)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, January-September 24, 1942 (10 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 21)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, September 26-December, 1942 (10 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 22)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, 1944 (12 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 23)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, January 6-late March, 1945 (14 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 24)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, May-October, 1945 (12 lvs) (Box 2, Folder 25)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, 1946-1948 (13 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 1)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, January 1949-October 1950 (13 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 2)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, January-July 11, 1951 (12 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 3)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, July 15-September, 1951 (14 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 4)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, March-May 20, 1952 (12 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 5)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, May 22-June 11, 1952 (12 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 6)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, June 17-June 28, 1952 (11 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 7)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, July-October, 1952 (14 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 8)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, 1953 (10 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 9)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, January-May 5, 1954 (12 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 10)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, May 15-June, 1954 (14 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 11)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, July-September 4, 1954 (13 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 12)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, September 13-October, 1954 (12 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 13)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, October-November, 1954 (9 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 14)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, 1955 (10 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 15)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, January-March, 1956 (10 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 16)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, April-June 4, 1956 (10 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 17)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, June-August, 1956 (10 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 18)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, August-October, 1956 (11 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 19)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, March-May 3, 1957 (10 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 20)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, May 8-June 7, 1957 (10 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 21)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, June 12-November, 1957 (13 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 22)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, January-June, 1958 (12 lvs) (Box 3, Folder 23)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, July-August, 1958 (13 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 1)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, September-December 7, 1958 (13 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 2)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, December 15, 1958-April 2, 1959 (12 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 3)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, April-July, 1959 (14 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 4)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, September 1959-March, 1960 (15 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 5)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, April-June, 1960 (13 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 6)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, June, 1960 (13 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 7)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, June-December, 1960 (17 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 8)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, February-May, 1961 (15 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 9)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, June-October, 1961 (15 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 10)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, October 10-November 14, 1961 (15 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 11)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, November 18-December, 1961(14 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 12)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, January-February, 1962 (12 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 13)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, March-April, 1962 (11 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 14)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, April-August, 1962 (13 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 15)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, September, 1962-June, 1963 (14 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 16)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, June 18-August 10, 1963 (13 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 17)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, August 13-November 20, 1963 (15 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 18)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, November 21, 1963-April, 1964 (13 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 19)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, June-October, 1964 (13 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 20)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, January-July 8, 1965 (17 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 21)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, July 10-December 28, 1965 (13 lvs) (Box 4, Folder 22)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, January-June 5, 1966 (12 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 1)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, June 9, 1966-January, 1967 (14 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 2)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, February, 1967-1968 (17 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 3)
- John Steinbeck to Pacific Biological Laboratories, n.d. (1 leaf) (Box 5, Folder 4)
- John Steinbeck to Edward Ricketts, 1946 (1 leaf) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- John Steinbeck to George F. Sensabaugh, [1941, 1942, or 1943] (2 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 6)
- John Steinbeck to Blanche Shipley Sheffield, 1923 (Carlton Sheffield's mother) (2 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 7)
- John Steinbeck to Carlton Sheffield, 1926-April, 1939 (11 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 8)
- John Steinbeck to Carlton Sheffield, June, 1939-1940 (13 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 9)
- John Steinbeck to Carlton Sheffield, 1944-1952 (12 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 10)
- John Steinbeck to Carlton Sheffield, 1953-November 8, 1962 (13 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 11)
- John Steinbeck to Carlton Sheffield, November 28, 1962-August, 1963 (13 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 12)
- John Steinbeck to Carlton Sheffield, September, 1963-March, 1965 (17 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 13)
- John Steinbeck to Carlton Sheffield, April, 1965-1968 (16 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 14)
- John Steinbeck to Marion Sheffield, 1923-1936 (10 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 15)
- John Steinbeck to Marion Sheffield, 1961 (9 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 16)
- John Steinbeck to Ruth Sheffield, 1926 (1 leaf) (Box 5, Folder 17)
- John Steinbeck to Stanford University Press, 1948-1949 (4 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 18)
- John Steinbeck to Robert Stein, 1965 (1 leaf) (Box 5, Folder 19)
- John Steinbeck to Carol Henning Steinbeck (Brown), 1962 (1 leaf) (Box 5, Folder 20)
- John Steinbeck to Gwendolyn Conger (Steinbeck), 1941 (1 leaf) (Box 5, Folder 21)
- John Steinbeck to Beatrice Steinbeck, 1945-September 5, 1962 (10 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 22)
- John Steinbeck to Stanford and Beatrice Steinbeck, September 13, 1962-October, 1962 (8 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 23)
- John Steinbeck to Margery Street, 1926 (5 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 24)
- John Steinbeck to Webster Street, ca. 1927/1928-October, 1941 (13 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 25)
- John Steinbeck to Webster Street, November, 1941-March, 1942 (15 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 26)
- John Steinbeck to Webster Street, April, 1942-June, 1942 (15 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 27)
- John Steinbeck to Webster Street, July, 1942-September, 1942 (14 lvs) (Box 5, Folder 28)
- John Steinbeck to Webster Street, October-November, 1942 (15 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 1)
- John Steinbeck to Webster Street, December, 1942-March 11, 1943 (14 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 2)
- John Steinbeck to Webster Street, March 13-April 14, 1943 (15 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 3)
- John Steinbeck to Webster Street, April 20-November, 1943 (13 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 4)
- John Steinbeck to Webster Street, December 13, 1943-1944 (13 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 5)
- John Steinbeck to Webster Street, [April 16, 1945]-November 27, 1945 (11 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 6)
- John Steinbeck to Webster Street, December, 1945-April, 1946 (15 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 7)
- John Steinbeck to Webster Street, May, 1947-December, 1948 (15 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 8)
- John Steinbeck to Webster Street, January, 1949-January 4, 1955 (13 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 9)
- John Steinbeck to Webster Street, March, 1955-March, 1956 (14 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 10)
- John Steinbeck to Webster Street, June, 1956-1968 (16 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 11)
- John Steinbeck to 20th Century Fox, 1944 (1 leaf) (Box 6, Folder 12)
- John Steinbeck to George Vellis, 1955 (1 leaf) (Box 6, Folder 13)
- John Steinbeck to Eugene Vinaver, 1957-June 22, 1958 (14 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 14)
- John Steinbeck to Eugene Vinaver, June 27, 1958-May 1, 1959 (10 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 15)
- John Steinbeck to Eugene Vinaver, May 2-August, 1959 (13 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 16)
- John Steinbeck to Eugene Vinaver, September, 1959-March, 1960 (13 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 17)
- John Steinbeck to Eugene Vinaver, July, 1960-June, 1965 (13 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 18)
- John Steinbeck to Eugene Vinaver, July, 1965-1966 (16 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 19)
- John Steinbeck to Max and Jack Wagner, [August 22, 1939]-[November 11, 1940] (10 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 20)
- John Steinbeck to Max and Jack Wagner, November 25, 1940-December 28, 1940, (11 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 21)
- John Steinbeck to Max and Jack Wagner, January, 1941-February, 1943 (14 lvs) (Box 6, Folder 22)
- John Steinbeck to Max and Jack Wagner, January, 1944-February, [1946] (15 lvs) (Box 7, Folder 1)
- John Steinbeck to Max and Jack Wagner, March, 1946-Summer, 1946 (15 lvs) (Box 7, Folder 2)
- John Steinbeck to Max and Jack Wagner, September, 1946-January 10,1947 (13 lvs) (Box 7, Folder 3)
- John Steinbeck to Max and Jack Wagner, January 16, 1947-July, 1947 (12 lvs) (Box 7, Folder 4)
- John Steinbeck to Max and Jack Wagner, 1949-1966 (15 lvs) (Box 7, Folder 5)
- John Steinbeck to Carl Wilhelmson, 1924-October 1, [1930] (14 lvs) (Box 7, Folder 6)
- John Steinbeck to Carl Wilhelmson, October 20, 1930-October 1, 1931 (14 lvs) (Box 7, Folder 7)
- John Steinbeck to Carl Wilhelmson, December, 1932-1938 (14 lvs) (Box 7, Folder 8)
- John Steinbeck to Carl Wilhelmson, 1939-1946 (13 lvs) (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Theodore Dreiser to John Steinbeck, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 10)
- Douglas Fairbanks, Jr. to John Steinbeck, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 11)
- Hartvig Kiran to John Steinbeck, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 12)
- A. Amasa Miller to John Steinbeck, 1929-1930 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Joan Rattner to John Steinbeck, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- Daniel Catton Rich to John Steinbeck, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Eugene F. Saxton to John Steinbeck, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Robert Stein to John Steinbeck, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 17)
- Webster Street to John Steinbeck, 1943, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 18)
- Jack Valenti to John Steinbeck, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 19)
- Eugene Vinaver to John Steinbeck, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Elizabeth Steinbeck Ainsworth to Beatrice and Stanford Steinbeck, Feb. 1969 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Barnaby Conrad to Warren R. Howell, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Copyright Office to A. Amasa Miller, April 1932 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Lord Crawford to Douglas Fairbanks, Jr., 1965 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Dodd, Mead and Company to A. Amasa Miller, April 1931 (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Douglas Fairbanks, Jr. to Eugene Vinaver, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Lynn Farnol to Webster F. Street, 1956 (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Stanley Gilson to George Vellis, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Ida Gordon to Eugene Vinaver, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- Mildred Lyman to Hartvig Kiran, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 30)
- A. Amasa Miller to Katherine Beswick, 1928 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- A. Amasa Miller to the Copyright Office, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- A. Amasa Miller to Robert M. McBride and Company, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- Elizabeth Otis to Joan Rattner, 1953 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- Post Office Department to A. Amasa Miller, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 35)
- Edmund Price to Beatrice and Stanford Steinbeck, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Daniel Catton Rich to Webster F. Street, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Stuart Rose, for Little, Brown, and Company to A. Amasa Miller, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Carol Henning Steinbeck to Carl Wilhelmson, 1930 (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Elaine Steinbeck to Harry Guggenheim, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Elaine Steinbeck to Carlton Sheffield, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- Elaine Steinbeck to Beatrice and Stanford Steinbeck, 1967-1972 (Box 7, Folder 42)
- Gwendolyn Conger Steinbeck to Peg Street, 1943 (Box 7, Folder 43)
- Gwendolyn Conger Steinbeck to Webster F. Street, 1941-1942 (Box 7, Folder 44)
- Gwendolyn Conger Steinbeck to Webster F, Street, 1942-1945 (Box 7, Folder 45)
- Webster F. Street to Hudson, Martin, and Ferranto, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 46)
- Webster F. Street to Daniel Cotton Rich, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 47)
- Webster F. Street to Shaw Artists Corporation, 1955 (Box 7, Folder 48)
- George Vellis to Shaw Artists Corporation, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Eugene Vinaver to the Nobel Committee of the Swedish Academy, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Stuart Ward to Albert Rosenshine, 1937 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- To Death And Life, Untitled Verse, 1923 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- A Lady in Infra-Red, typescript, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- A Lady in Infra-Red, photocopy (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Cup of Gold, pp. 1-54, typescript with corrections, 1926-1927 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Cup of Gold, pp. 55-102, typescript with corrections, 1926-1927 (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Tahoe Epic, typescript, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 9)
- Ballad of Quid Pro Quo, typescript, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 10)
- The White Sister of Fourteenth Street, typescript with corrections (Box 8, Folder 11)
- The White Sister of Fourteenth Street, (photocopy) (Box 8, Folder 12)
- The Murder, typescript (Box 8, Folder 13)
- The Green Lady, (dramatic piece: 3rd draft), 1927-1938 (Box 8, Folder 14)
- The Green Lady: a novel, pp. 1-27, typescript (Box 8, Folder 15)
- The Green Lady: a novel, pp. 28-54, typescript (Box 8, Folder 16)
- The Green Lady: a novel, pp. 55-81, typescript (Box 8, Folder 17)
- The Green Lady: a novel, pp. 82-107, typescript (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Carlton Sheffield's Review of Record Book, 1929-1931 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- The Red Pony, script, pp. 1-45 (Box 8, Folder 20)
- The Red Pony, script, pp. 46-91 (Box 8, Folder 21)
- The Red Pony, script, pp. 92-136 (Box 8, Folder 22)
- The Red Pony, script, pp. 1-45 (photocopy) (Box 8, Folder 23)
- The Red Pony, script, pp. 46-91 (photocopy) (Box 8, Folder 24)
- The Red Pony, script, pp. 92-136 (photocopy) (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Cannery Row, fragments (photocopy) (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Between Pacific Tides, foreword, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Narration of Flight, ca. 1960 (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Nobel Prize Speech (Box 8, Folder 29)
- Manila Folder addressed to C.A. Sheffield, ca. April, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 30)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1931-1937 (Box 9, Folder 1)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1938-1939 (Box 9, Folder 2)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1939-1940 (Box 9, Folder 3)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1940-1941 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1941-1945 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1945-1949 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1949-1952 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1952-1954 (Box 9, Folder 8)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1954 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1955-1957 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1957-1958 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1958-1959 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1959-1961 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1961-1962 (Box 10, Folder 7)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 1)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1963-1965 (Box 11, Folder 2)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, typescripts, 1965-1968 (Box 11, Folder 3)
- John Steinbeck to Elizabeth Otis, carbons, 1942-1960 (Box 11, Folder 4)
- Typescripts of Minor Pieces: To An Elephant Who Was Sad; untitled piece regarding Robert Capa; The Articles of War; Are We Morally Flabby; Surging Thirties; untitled regarding the history of the migrant people since The Grapes of Wrath; untitled regarding Steinbeck's typing. (Box 11, Folder 5)
- Typescripts of Minor Pieces: untitled article regarding Carl Sandburg; Untitled Piece; Atque Vale, Some Random Thoughts on Life Insurance as An Anti-survival Factor in the American Male; list of aphorisms, Egg Heads of the World Arise; Introduction; Circus. (Box 11, Folder 6)
- Typescripts of Minor Pieces: Old Cars; River Folk: A Sketch; A Pox on All Your Ages; Manuscript for Holiday Magazine; An Innocent Journey; The Red Pony Suite; El Camion Vacilador. (Box 11, Folder 7)
- Typescripts of Minor Pieces: She was a Widgeon of Delight; The Excavations under St. Peter; Monagesque Fallout; The Queen's Birthday; Three Coins Down theDrain; London Interview; Midsummer; Clean out the Icebox; A Desperate Remedy; Gusher, Florentine Fashion; Sholokoff; Explode Sweet Chariot; See Naples and Die; Mare Nostrum; It's a Treat to Beat your Feet; Homesickness. (Box 11, Folder 8)
- Letters to Alicia, carbons and originals, 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 9)
- Letters to Alicia, carbons and originals, 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 10)
- Letters to Alicia, carbons and originals, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 11)
- Letters to Alicia, carbons and originals, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 12)
- Letters to Alicia, carbons and originals, 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 13)
- Tearsheets and photocopies of John Steinbeck pieces (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Tearsheets and photocopies of John Steinbeck pieces (Box 12, Folder 2)
- Tearsheets and photocopies of John Steinbeck pieces (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Tearsheets and photocopies of John Steinbeck pieces (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Reviews and articles about John Steinbeck, 1937-1952 (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Reviews and articles about John Steinbeck, 1952-1977 (Box 12, Folder 6)
- Reviews and articles about John Steinbeck (Box 12, Folder 7)
- Reviews and articles about John Steinbeck (Box 12, Folder 8)
- Reviews and articles about John Steinbeck (Box 12, Folder 9)
- Reviews and articles about John Steinbeck (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Reviews and articles about John Steinbeck (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Reviews and articles about John Steinbeck (Box 12, Folder 12)
- Reviews and articles about John Steinbeck (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Articles about John Steinbeck's life, 1937-1959 (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Articles about John Steinbeck's life, 1960-1967 (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Articles about John Steinbeck's life, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Articles about John Steinbeck's life, 1969 (Box 13, Folder 4)